[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
[Camia] Since the beginning,
he's caused nothing
but trouble for your father.
I just hope he's changed.
[Damian] Who are you?
-Damian?
-Camia?
[Camia] Damian, you look
exactly like Dante.
If you aren't careful,
that family might target you,
just like what they did to Dante.
What did the Ardientes do to my brother?
Dante was killed
by the most powerful family
in Poblacion Ardiente.
Emilia Ardiente was the one behind it.
[Emilia] Why did you have
Aunt Claire killed?
Is it because you have a secret
you want to stay hidden?
[Julio] You tell me your secrets,
and I'll tell you mine.
How did my beautiful daughter
get out of jail?
Someone helped her out.
A group of men, and a guy in a mask.
I want to see your face.
I'll accept you, no matter who you are.
[Julio] Are you sure
Miss Aguas is responsible
for this screwup?
Yes, I'm sure, Congressman.
You're finally awake.
Hold on, I'll fix you some breakfast.
[Damian] I'm sorry, Dante.
Looks like I won't just be
reclaiming Jaguar's identity.
I'll be taking Camia's love
from you, as well.
[Loring] Vote at the elections tomorrow.
The voices of the people
of Ardiente need to be heard.
[Diego] Get out of here
if you don't want to ruin
Julio Ardiente's name.
[Diego] Slowly, Uncle.
[Pandoy groaning] Thank you.
[exhales]
They've gone too far.
They're abusing us.
They've gone too far!
I won't… I won't let them
get away with this!
Diego, stop.
Don't let everything our supporters
worked hard for go to waste
by going to the Ardientes' place alone.
First, it was Aunt Camia.
This time, they went after
you and Uncle Pandoy.
Who will they target next? Tell me.
Which of us will be next?
Diego, the election is in two days.
If they won't cheat, I know you'll win.
So we need to watch
this election carefully.
[Jepoy] She's right, Diego.
We will support you.
That's right. This will be over soon.
[tense music playing]
Thank you, Jaguar, but I need
to go back to the mansion
to find out the truth about my mother.
If I give you what you want,
you might decide to stay.
But, if I reveal my identity to you…
how can I be sure that you won't leave me?
[Ivy] Yes, Congressman?
Sit down. Sit down, Ivy.
Um…
Sanggano here tells me…
that you didn't help him
in finding the money Diego took.
Instead, you just went on your own way.
It makes me wonder…
where did the money go?
[unsettling music playing]
Does Diego have it?
Or do you?
[scoffs]
So just because Col. Sanggano said that,
you already think I'm going
against you, Congressman?
It's my money, Congressman.
You can have my company
investigated if you want,
but you won't find
the 50 million pesos there.
Just because he failed to catch Diego,
Col. Sanggano's already making up stories.
So now, you're suddenly blaming me.
Oh. No, no.
I'm not blaming you.
I'm not pointing fingers.
I just want to make sure
that I still have your loyalty,
Miss Aguas.
You shouldn't question
my loyalty, Congressman.
You have my utmost loyalty.
[inhales deeply]
I'm not like your daughter,
who's ready to betray you.
[laughs]
It takes intelligent people
to mount a plot of revenge.
And clearly,
Emilia does not have the mettle
for it even if she wanted to.
[chuckles]
Well, Congressman, she surprised me.
I thought Emilia wasn't
an intelligent woman.
But I was wrong.
Do you want me to tell you
who helped her escape?
No need to stand, Congressman.
The one who helped Emilia escape
was no other than…
Jaguar.
[tense music intensifies]
It's Jaguar.
They've been talking, meeting,
and planning to take you down
for a while now.
Well, if you still have doubts…
Take a look at this.
Proof.
After you look at it, Congressman,
I'll let you decide whether
you'll believe in me
or in Col. Sanggano here.
Oh! Happy watching!
Colonel, give me that.
[suspenseful music playing]
-[man] Boss Jaguar.
-[man 2] Boss.
[Emilia] Jaguar.
[suspenseful music intensifies]
[gunshot]
Shut that infernal thing down!
Oh! Emilia, Emilia!
How could you?!
You slimy snake!
That Jaguar guy is just
fooling you, Emilia.
Papa, that's why I need
to meet up with him,
so I can turn the tables on him.
I want you to kill him,
so I won't have any more problems.
Okay, Papa.
I'll do exactly what you want me to do.
[Julio] I would like you to take care of
one of our enemies.
Kill Jaguar.
For the sake of our family.
[unsettling music playing]
Jaguar.
Emilia, if really do want
to head back home,
then I won't stop you anymore.
But, there's something you should know.
[suspenseful music swelling]
The Ardientes' men!
[gunshots]
Get inside!
Tell Boss Jaguar we're
being attacked by the Ardientes!
[gunshots]
Boss Jaguar!
-We're being attacked…
-Oh my God!
-by Julio's men!
-Huh?!
[gunshots]
Emilia, you have to get
out of here! Leave this to us.
-I can't just leave you here!
-There's no time! Just go!
-Jaguar, no!
-Give me the gun!
No, Jaguar! Jaguar!
-Come with us, Emilia Torillo!
-[exclaims] Let go of me!
[grunts] I said, let go!
-[Emilia] Papa? Papa!
-[Julio] Hmm?
[Julio] That's close enough.
[Julio scoffs]
Fancy seeing you here, Emilia.
You know what?
I've been waiting for you
since the other day
you promised to come over.
But, for some reason, you never showed up.
But then, I realized…
My daughter must be enjoying
herself at her new house.
Spending time with her new
live-in partner,
also known as…
Jaguar?
[stutters] Papa, let me explain.
[Julio shouts] There's nothing to discuss!
Jaguar was the one who helped you escape.
You have been working with him all along!
I remembered! I remembered!
I asked you countless times for his head!
Countless times!
But you never delivered.
And now, I know why.
Because you're nothing but a slut
who's been fooling
around with that bastard!
You're worse than a dog in heat!
I'm sorry, Papa.
I'm sorry, please forgive me.
I'm sorry.
Get out!
Sorry! Sorry! I'm sorry, Papa!
Get yourself out of here
before I kill you!
No! No, Papa!
-Get out of my house!
-[Emilia] No…
And never set foot in this house again!
I forbid you!
Don't set foot in this house!
Please, Papa! Forgive me!
And now, you wonder, you seriously wonder,
why I never loved you?
Take a good look at yourself!
This is precisely why
I could not love you!
Because you're no different…
from your treacherous mother!
You're just like her!
Get out of my house!
-Get out!
-[gunshot]
-Papa!
-Get out of the house!
[wailing] Papa!
-Get out!
-Papa!
-[Julio sobs]
-[tense music intensifies]
Emilia Ardiente-Torillo,
the second person on my list.
I swore to myself
I'd make your father disown you.
That you'd be stripped
of both your title and your dignity.
Mission accomplished.
As they say, the most dangerous foe
is the one who pretends to be a friend.
That's the lesson
you'll be learning in the end,
because you're next on my list,
Julio Ardiente.
I'm here for you, Congressman.
Papa!
[sobs]
[Julio] Take a good look at yourself!
This is precisely why
I could not love you!
Because you're no different…
from your treacherous mother!
[monitor beeping rhythmically]
[Julio exhales]
So, Congressman…
looks like I've proven
my loyalty to you once again.
I apologize for doubting you.
I should've known not to expect
anything else from Emilia
other than failure and betrayal.
Miss Ivy Aguas…
From this day forward, we only
have each other to rely on.
So, let's not screw it up.
Do you really have to keep reminding me
not to break your trust?
Congressman Julio,
you should know by now that
I'm the strongest ally you have left.
Now, it's my turn to remind you, Julio.
Don't try me, Congressman.
[tense music swelling]
Jaguar!
Those are Papa's men.
Where are you, Jaguar?
[man laughs]
[suspenseful music playing]
Jaguar.
Boss Jaguar,
Julio's men are still at our headquarters.
-[thumps]
-[exhales]
Looks like those pests
don't plan to leave.
I think it's time
to look for a new hideout.
[voice prompt] The subscriber
cannot be reached.
Please try again later.
[sets phone down]
[tense music playing]
[upbeat drums music playing]
[music continues]
[camera shutters click]
[Loring] Just a few more hours.
Diego, this is the day
we've been waiting for.
Though I can't say I'm fine
with accepting defeat.
Because I believe
you're going to be the winner.
I know you're meant to be the governor.
That's right!
That's right… I will be
the governor of this town.
For a new Ardiente!
[all] To the new Ardiente!
-[cheers and applause]
-Diego!
[all] Go Diego! Go Diego! Go Diego!
Go Diego! Go Diego! Go Diego!
Is that your
final price?
I think you're putting too
much value on your position
as Election Commissioner Secretary.
Leandro Marquez.
Congressman, if you really
want to win, then,
you have to make the investment.
Besides, I'm sure you'll earn back
whatever you invested once
you're governor, correct?
I'll think about it.
I'll call you back.
Sure. I'm only one call
away, Congressman.
One call away from your victory.
You bloodsucking leech!
Colonel, I have a plan.
And in this plan,
my victory will be certain.
We won't have to bribe anyone
or negotiate with anybody.
We'll just have to blow things up.
So that people against me can't vote.
[suspenseful music]
[scoffs]
Excuse me. Can I use your phone?
I need to use your phone.
Ten pesos for a call.
Don't demand something
if you can't pay for it.
How dare you!
Don't you know that I can buy your store?
I can even buy you.
So-- Ew, don't touch me! Gross.
Who do you think you are?
Wait, aren't you the former governor?
Yes. I am Emilia Ardiente-Torillo.
Now, maybe you can let me use your phone?
Aren't you supposed to be in jail?
Wait.
Hey! Hey, get back here!
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
Ma'am, here's your bill.
Where's your restroom?
-Over there.
-There?
-Yes.
-Okay. Thank you.
-Sure.
-Thank you very much.
-[Emilia exclaims]
-Ma'am! Ma'am! Ma'am!
[suspenseful music playing]
[suspenseful music continues]
[truck engine starts]
[news anchor] And in
Poblacion Ardiente news,
the first batch of voting machines
just arrived last night.
They will be used by 10
of the province's towns.
And this morning, the remaining towns
will be receiving their voting machines.
[Julio] My victory will be certain.
We won't have to bribe anyone
or negotiate with anybody.
We'll just have to blow things up.
-What's happening?
-I've been here for hours.
-It's been delayed for so long.
-[voters clamoring]
[election officer 1] I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
We're having some technical problems!
-Don't tell me it's what I think it is.
-Wait. You can't vote yet.
The voting machines
from Manila got delayed.
-Really?
-When are they arriving?
-Let's just be patient.
-Miss…
the other towns have already voted.
-Meanwhile, we've been here for hours.
-Yeah.
-Please don't worry.
-And we still haven't voted yet.
The voting machines are
arriving, they're on their way.
-But when?
-They're coming from Manila?!
-Yes, on its way.
-We have somewhere else to be.
-You'll be able to vote.
-We never know what's happening.
[woman] Geez!
They might blow up the truck.
The same one carrying voting machines
that are coming in from Manila.
-What?
-Diego, a lot of voters
won't be able to vote
if they blow up the machines.
I've got an idea. Come with me.
I bet the truck from Manila
definitely has a bomb.
One that can be detonated
with a cell phone.
If it's really from Manila,
a checkpoint would have spotted the bomb.
My guess is they'll plant
the bomb here in Ardiente.
Let's just follow them.
[suspenseful music playing]
[suspenseful music continues]
Let's go! Hurry!
[explosion]
[Diego] Are you okay?
-Are you all right?
-I'm fine.
[reporter 1] It was revealed
that the voting machines
which exploded were
supposed to be delivered
to the neighborhood where a majority
of Diego Torillo's supporters reside.
And now, we're here
with Mr. Diego Torillo.
Mr. Diego Torillo, what can
you say about what happened?
I'm sure that the Ardientes
are responsible for this.
[Diego] They bombed the truck
that was supposed
to deliver voting machines
to the neighborhood where
most of my supporters reside.
It's so obvious that they are
trying to sabotage my votes.
[Charlie] Thank you, Mr. Diego Torillo.
With the explosion of the said
voting machines,
will it be a victory for Julio Ardiente?
And is it true that
the Ardientes are responsible
for the explosion?
Stay tuned for updates.
This is Charlie Costanilla, reporting.
What a brilliant plan!
Son of a gun, Julio!
You're the bomb.
Ivy, does this mean
the election will be postponed?
If so, that old man will definitely win!
Mom, they can't postpone the election.
Don't worry. Diego is already
doing everything he can.
Julio can't sabotage our votes.
Diego is making sure that won't happen.
[door opens]
[door closes]
Lily. Been there long?
Uh. Uncle, I just arrived.
Have you eaten?
Mom, can we talk in private?
Lily.
What did you want to talk about?
Mom, it's Uncle Damian.
He escaped.
He was never released from jail.
Mom, you need to be careful.
I think it was a bad idea to take him in
and take care of him.
It's dangerous for you.
Your uncle said that he's a changed man
and that he runs a business in Manila.
Mom, if he lied about his escape,
maybe we shouldn't trust him so much.
You're right, Lily.
But we can't just ask him to leave
when his injuries haven't healed.
He needs us.
Mom, I'm just worried about you.
You need to be careful.
[phone dings]
Julio just texted. I need to go.
Thank you, dear.
And don't worry. I'll be careful.
See you soon.
[exhales]
[tense music playing]
[mouths] Thank you.
[tense music continues playing]
[supporters] Ardiente! Ardiente!
Ardiente! Ardiente!
Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente!
Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente!
[election officer 2] Silence, please!
Be considerate of other voters!
Voters, please fall in line properly!
[election officer 1] I'm sorry.
Please wait outside.
We haven't set up.
-Come on. Hurry.
-When will the machines arrive?
[election officer 1] Please wait for them.
The other neighborhood has
already cast its votes.
[woman 1] Yeah.
Meanwhile, we've been here for hours,
but voting still hasn't started!
What's wrong?
-Isn't it?
-[woman 1] That's true.
Wait. Wait.
[Loring] How come they're already set up?
What's going on? What's happening?
-We apologize.
-What time is it?
What's going on here?
The voting machines for our
neighborhood haven't arrived.
Please be patient.
-We're wasting time!
-Oh, good grief.
[man] What is that?
-What… what is that?
-[man] What's happening now?
Look! They've already set up.
What happened to our voting machines?
I have a bad feeling about this!
Look! They're almost done!
I know, Auntie.
[man] I know this is on purpose…
No one else is capable of doing
this other than Julio Ardiente.
This can't be!
We can't just keep waiting here.
We can't just stand here and do nothing.
Look! We all came here to vote!
We should demand our rights
and ask the government
to give us a chance to vote…
That's right! Yeah!
…with or without the machines!
Yeah!
Right! We need to cast our votes in
for the one who deserves to win,
and that's Diego!
-Diego!
-[applause]
-[man] Diego!
I don't think the congressman
is responsible
for the bombing of the truck
carrying their voting machines.
[woman] I'm sure Diego's
supporters just made that up
because they know that he'll lose.
[scoffs] You're right.
[tense music continues playing]
You know, violence isn't
the key to winning an election.
I'm sure Diego's camp wouldn't do that.
Do you hear what you're saying?
Are you really a supporter
of the Ardientes?
Or is Diego Torillo your bet
for the position of governor?
Young boy, please
don't be rude to Miss Aguas.
Sorry, Congressman.
Mister, I am Ivy Aguas.
I'm one with the Ardientes.
That's why I'm on
the same line as you are.
Sorry, ma'am.
[man] Did you see that?
Wow. Let's just cast our votes.
-Let's just vote.
-Yeah.
[indistinct chatter]
[tense music continues playing]
[election officer]
Here's the voting machine.
[indistinct chatter]
[tense music continues playing]
[supporters] Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente!
[man] Long live the Ardientes!
[overlapping chants]
[supporters] Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente!
Ardiente! Ardiente! Ardiente!
-Long live the Congressman!
-Long live!
-Long live the Ardientes!
[man] Long live Ardiente!
[music fading]
[tense music playing]
[Julio clears throat]
Diego Torillo.
Where is your…
white flag?
Didn't you come here to surrender?
I know you were behind the explosion.
But no matter what you do,
you will never succeed.
Julio, if you win,
our people will be lucky
if you decide to share the money
your family plundered.
But we all know you would never do that.
Because for you,
there are only two solutions.
Violence and murder.
[Diego] That is why…
we will never allow someone
like you to lead this province.
[chuckles]
The two of you are so self-righteous.
How can you be sure
I was behind the explosion?
What do I care if someone
blew up the voting machines?
It'll barely have an effect
on the results.
Besides, those votes weren't all for you.
You two are a little too self-assured.
Julio!
Forty percent of voters
won't be able to vote
because of the explosion.
But don't worry.
We're doing everything we can
to get new voting machines,
so we can vote.
[Diego] We would rather die…
than leave Poblacion Ardiente
in your hands.
And before I die,
I'll make sure that
this town will not fall
into the hands of someone like you.
Julio, your time is up.
Because I'll make sure that
from this day on,
evil will no longer reign in Ardiente.
[Diego] Excuse me.
[tense music playing]
Auntie…
I'll just go over there.
[indistinct chatter]
[Anna] Diego.
[Loring] Diego.
The sun's about to set,
and we still haven't voted!
The machines aren't even here yet.
What are we going to do?
Miss Camia, the voting machines are here.
We can set them up now.
-They are?
-Yes.
That's good to hear.
Don't worry, Nanny.
Everyone, if the voting machines
don't arrive today,
I'll make sure you all get to vote
first thing tomorrow morning.
-Thank you!
-Just don't lose hope!
Miss Loring! Everyone.
I have some good news!
[line rings]
Martel! What is this?
Well?! What are these new
voting machines I'm seeing?
Didn't we talk about this?
And now, I see two of them
being set up directly
in my rival's polling place?!
Oh. Here come the voting machines!
-Hooray!
-Now, we can vote!
[crowd cheering, whooping]
-Come one, let's line up!
-We can now vote!
The public is keeping a close eye on us.
They think the Ardientes
are very corrupt and violent.
Corrupt?
Violent?
Are you out of your mind?!
Haven't you seen the statistics?
Poblacion Ardiente has a zero crime rate!
Nobody believes that blatant
lie anymore, Julio.
You should know better.
But that being said,
the whole country is focused
on the result of that election.
If I don't give in to the public's demand
for new voting machines,
it'll be another point against you.
Son of a gun!
[applause]
[cheering and whooping]
[Diego] Let's go, everyone!
-[cheering and whooping]
-[Pandoy] It's here!
[election officer 1]
Let's line up everyone.
-[applause]
-[overlapping chatter]
You're going to be the governor for sure!
[cheering and whooping]
Everybody! Let's line up!
[Loring] Let's go! Come on!
[cheers and laughter]
[cheering and chattering continue]
[soft music playing]
[Anna] Congrats!
[Diego] Let's line up!
Let's line up! Okay! Auntie.
Diego!
Auntie, thank goodness
we can finally vote.
That's because you never give up.
It's because we never give up.
[giggles]
-Let's go, Auntie.
-Let's start.
[Camia giggles]
[ominous music]
[upbeat drums music playing]
[music continues]
[music stops]
[reporter] After a long period of waiting,
the citizens of Sto. Niño
were finally able to vote
with the eventual arrival
of new voting machines.
This includes gubernatorial candidate
Diego Ardiente-Torillo.
[tense music playing]
[tense music intensifies]
[Camia] Dante was killed
by the most powerful family
in Poblacion Ardiente years ago.
Emilia Ardiente was the one behind it.
I really shouldn't care whether
or not they killed you.
Now is my chance to have Camia.
[sighs] But, no.
The Ardientes killed my brother.
They killed Dante without mercy!
I want you, Jaguar.
I want to marry you. Please!
If only I'd known how that woman, Emilia,
was the one who had my brother killed,
I wouldn't have let her get out alive
the first time we met.
You, Emilia, are the one responsible
for my brother's death.
I'll make sure you pay for what you did.
[Emilia groaning]
Where is this place?
Can you help me, please, mister?
[groans] My gosh!
Where am I?
Oh.
I want to apologize for riding
in the back of your truck.
It was never my intention.
And, I'm really sorry for that.
[no audible dialogue]
So, if you'll excuse me, please.
Thanks for these too.
[whooping] I'm in Manila!
[laughs] And I still haven't
gotten caught!
Isn't that amazing?
[sighs contentedly]
[whoops] Manila. Manila.
[sighs]
Now, it's time to contact Jaguar.
-Looks like she's lost.
-So, wanna nab her?
-Yeah, let's follow her.
-Sure.
[Anna] Please give them some sandwiches.
Hello, everyone!
[Anna] I'm sure they're all hungry.
Let's take a little break.
I'm sure you're all pretty hungry.
-[applause]
-Dig in.
[Danny] Thank you, Governor.
-[Loring] Pandoy!
-[Fernan] Come on, Pandoy.
[Camia] Pandoy is very hungry.
Come back if you want some more!
-[Loring] You're still running.
-[Diego] Here.
-You might hurt yourself.
-Here, Uncle. Some juice.
Thank you.
[Jepoy] Diego.
As early as now,
I want to congratulate you.
You really deserve to be governor.
Thanks.
Well then, in a couple of hours,
we'll find out whether all our efforts
will bring us the bacon.
Don't worry.
I'm sure victory will be yours.
All right then, excuse me.
[Julio] Please, enjoy the meal.
-Congratulations!
-Oh. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
-I can't wait for the results.
-[laughs]
Congressman.
-Hi, Miss Aguas.
-I mean, Governor.
-[chuckles]
-Congrats!
Thank you, thank you, Miss Aguas.
You know, you've been
a big help to this campaign.
You're one of the people
behind this success.
Even in the early days
of Arnaldo's campaign.
You are one of the reasons
why the Ardientes
will continue to rule this land.
This land that was named after our family.
-Congressman.
-Yes?
Diego's in the lead in most
of the neighborhoods.
Don't panic, dear.
This fight isn't over.
Let's all just celebrate, okay?
-Yes.
-Go on, don't worry.
[tense music playing]
[reporter] Diego has a lead
over Congressman Julio Ardiente
in the votes.
[people exclaim]
We won't lose hope. You will win, Diego.
[Emilia] An Ardiente never loses.
I will always be an Ardiente,
and no one can take that away from me.
I will rise up and destroy you all.
[Julio] My grandson. Victory is yours.
Tell me who should pay.
[theme music playing]